<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>Klare</title>
  <id>/</id>
  <link href="/" />
  <link href="//atom.xml" rel="self" />
  <updated>2015-12-07T15:32:58-08:00</updated>
  <rights>Copyright 2014, Klare Frank</rights>
  <author>
    <name>Klare Frank</name>
  </author>
  
    <entry>
      <title>How to Work Remotely Without Losing Your Mind</title>
      <link href="//how-to-work-remotely.html" />
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;It’s been a little over a year since I started working for Treehouse, which meant giving up the office lifestyle. My previous experience working remotely was relegated to a few snow days stuck in southern Delaware and days before holidays.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;1. Have a separate work and home computer&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&#39;s sort of a nod to my days working in government, but I firmly believe that work should be kept separate from anything else you do on a computer. I might close one laptop at the end of the work day and immediately open another, but the perception that I&#39;m leaving work for the day helps. I don&#39;t have any work related development environments set up on my ‘home’ computer (my macbook air), so the temptation to just do one more thing isn&#39;t there. There are some exceptions, like traveling. Lugging around both my macbook pro and my air seemed ridiculous when I moved from DC to Seattle, stopping on vacation for the weekend in Vegas. I usually only take my pro with me when traveling because light travel superceeds other priorities for me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;2. Have a dedicated work area&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But don&#39;t feel like you have to work from there all the time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since I started at Treehouse, I&#39;ve had a dedicated desk at WeWork that houses my 27&quot; monitor and a much more traditional setup. For a while, I had trouble working on anything BUT that monitor, so it helped to set it up someplace that was out of my apartment where I knew would be quiet and I could get things done. Since I&#39;ve done a ton of traveling this year, I&#39;ve gotten more used to multi-tasking on my laptop, but it&#39;s still nice to know I have a dedicated workstation where I can absolutely get my work done.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, I get a lot of benefit from switching up my working locations. I find that I&#39;m much more inspired when creating new design work if I go to someplace I don&#39;t usually work from. Taking advantage of the mobility that comes with working remotely has been great, so I don&#39;t try to force myself to go into an office everyday (just most days).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;3. Get out of your house/apartment every day&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This was crucial when I lived in a 400 sq foot studio in DC. Since in person interaction was no longer a necessary part of my day to day, it was really easy to stay in for more than a day at a time. I might have some reserved tendancies, but for the most part, I&#39;m at my happiest when I get to talk to someone at least once every day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Going outside every day is also crucial in the Winter, to get some more sunlight and vitamin D. I only had one set of windows in my studio that looked out onto another (taller) apartment building, so the amount of light coming in was pretty small. Now that I&#39;m in Seattle, I get less amount of light in the Winter overall, so I&#39;m trying to be proactive about taking in that sunlight when I can (even if it&#39;s behind clouds most of the time).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And if it&#39;s raining, you don&#39;t have to go outside, but just get out and switch locations for a little while.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are some other things that might be good practices, such as not lounging in your pjs all day and waking up early, but overall, I&#39;ve found these things to be more every day things than work day things (with some exceptions, of course). I&#39;d also love to have more designers to interact with on a daily basis in-person, but this is more of a nice to have and not a must have.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Overall, my criteria for keeping sane involves providing myself with enough tools to get my work done efficiently, and keeping myself happy by providing enough in-person interaction that I don&#39;t get from a job daily.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary>
      <id>//how-to-work-remotely.html</id>
      <updated>2015-12-07T07:07:51-08:00</updated>
      <author>
        <name>Klare Frank</name>
      </author>
    </entry>
  
    <entry>
      <title>The Top 10 Terminal Commands Every New Designer Should Know</title>
      <link href="//terminal-commands.html" />
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;You’ve probably experienced a time you’ve had a developer just sigh and take your computer from you instead of watching you entering in code to a scary looking terminal window. Wouldn’t you rather know a little bit of what they’re up to? Wouldn’t you rather figure out the basic commands of knowing how to use git (which you’ll inevitably have to use at some point)?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These are the &lt;em&gt;very&lt;/em&gt; basics, but they’ll certainly help with getting you familiar with using terminal and not feeling as scared about deleting everything on your computer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First off, you can start using the command line by opening up the Terminal app. The easiest way to do this is to search Spotlight (shortcut: cmd + space) for Terminal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Some basic file management/navigating around files stuff&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;1. cd&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Stands for change directory (or folder). You can use this command to navigate into a folder.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;cd work/my-project
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Similarly, you can navigate up, or out of a folder by adding ../ to the beginning:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;cd ../
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;2. ls&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Stands for list. Lists out the contents of a folder or directory. If I want to see the contents of my Dev folder, I&#39;d type:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;ls Dev
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;...and then press enter. If your folder were named Development instead, you&#39;d use the next command to save you a little time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;3. Tab&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Completes arguments. If you’re drilling down into a directory, use tab to finish the folder name so you don’t have to memorize it (or worry about spelling it wrong).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;4. Up and Down Arrow Keys&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This will let you navigate through previous commands you’ve already entered. I’ve found it’s especially helpful when using git add and push or when you need to remember that command that dev told you to use and you haven’t cleared your window.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;5. mkdir&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Stands for make directory. Enter in:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;mkdir new-project
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To create a new folder within the directory you’re in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;6. rm&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Removes. You can use this to, say, remove the directory you just created. (Hint: use tab to complete the directory name.) This command also removes files, but be careful because they do not go to the trash can. Instead, they’re deleted immediately.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;rm new-project/
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;7. mv&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Created a stylesheet, but it’s in the wrong folder? Use the mv command to move the file to the correct folder.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;mv style.css /stylesheets
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;8. clear&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Clears the current window. Have your terminal window cluttered up with stuff and just want to not be distracted? Enter the clear command to start fresh.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Things to help you with development&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;9. What to do when you a git command and it opens this weird view you can’t get out of&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’ve ever tried to do a git commit and forgot to add a message, it’ll switch views to something that you might have trouble getting out of. This is git opening up vim for you to edit something. All you need to do to exit is:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;:wq
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This means write (or save) and quite. (Yes you need the colon.) Press enter and it should go back to the view that’s more familiar. If that doesn’t work, try adding an exclamation point to the end.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Extra points if you actually type a commit message before quitting!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;10. Start a webserver for a directory&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This’ll let you view websites you’re building or testing locally. First, cd into the directory or folder you want and then enter this command:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;python -m SimpleHTTPServer
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re having trouble with the port number already being in use, add a different number onto the end of the statement. Ex:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;python -m SimpleHTTPServer 8080
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;More points&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Intimidated when people say you should learn something like Vim, but don’t know where to start? You can enter vimtutor as a command and start learning immediately.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;vimtutor
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s right. Terminal comes with a built in way to learn how to use it’s code editor, so no excuses.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Interested in learning more about how to use the command line? Check out &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/jlevy/the-art-of-command-line&quot;&gt;The Art of Command Line&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary>
      <id>//terminal-commands.html</id>
      <updated>2015-06-18T09:57:51-07:00</updated>
      <author>
        <name>Klare Frank</name>
      </author>
    </entry>
  
    <entry>
      <title>A designer’s perspective on solo travel</title>
      <link href="//a-designers-perspective-on-solo-travel.html" />
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Anyone who talks with me regularly will tell you that I have a strong case of wanderlust. If I haven’t traveled anywhere in a while, my conversations will usually include something along the lines of ‘Damn, I can’t wait to get out of here and go to ____’, tips on searching for cheap plane flights, or lol’ing at myself because I booked a flight without taking a second to think about it. Traveling tends to occupy a good portion of my thoughts, but I attribute it to my thirst for continually new experiences and having spent most of my college years majoring in Global Studies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Things I’ve Learned From Solo Travel&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;1. Trust that things will work out&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My most recent trip to Croatia and Slovenia involved a lot of traveling to get to my next destination. Altogether, I took five flights, one bus, two trains, and rented a car to drive about five hours. I was paranoid that every one of my travel arrangements wouldn’t work out and spent a lot of time researching on tripadvisor about other people’s experiences prior to traveling.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://igcdn-photos-e-a.akamaihd.net/hphotos-ak-xfa1/t51.2885-15/11055644_371692649690612_1050535963_n.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Dubrovnik&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But the bus from Dubrovnik to Split was waiting at the bus station when I arrived, clearly marked and impossible not to spot, and left promptly with only around fifteen people occupying the coach seats.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The car rental agency didn’t even ask any questions when I offered up a debit card instead of credit. I didn’t even have to turn on the GPS to find my way out of the city onto the main highway because the signage was so clear and hard not to miss.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I purchased my train ticket an hour before I was leaving Zagreb, the attendant spoke very little English, but I was able to communicate a round-trip ticket to Ljubljana. Even though I probably had a very confused look on my face when she handed me a ticket with handwritten destinations, I was able to get from Zagreb to Ljubljana and back painlessly (even with border control).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://igcdn-photos-c-a.akamaihd.net/hphotos-ak-xaf1/t51.2885-15/11015602_1617397625160658_187306894_n.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Border Control between Croatia and Slovenia&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you’re traveling alone, there’s no one there to ask dumb questions to reassure yourself that everything’s going to work out just fine. But it’s not worth the extra pain involved in worrying if you got the right address, or if you communicated the right thing, or if the train you’re about to get on is actually going to the city you want (tip: just check the time, trains are pretty punctual). Things will work out more often than not, and if it doesn’t, hey, it’s an adventure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I’m designing, especially in UX, there’s usually a need to thoroughly research everything and while this is great for figuring out if users know where to click or if you’re really off from your target goal, most of the time there’s more than one solution. The amount of time spent researching might reveal that one solution is a little bit better than another, but is it worth the time spent researching beforehand or would it have just been better to launch and tweek later? (I lean more towards the latter.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;2. Learn to let go a bit of control&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Along those lines, it’s really easy to want to know all the details of something before getting into a project or going on a trip. Quite a few years ago, I used to have so much anxiety about going anywhere new that I’d make sure to look on a map beforehand. And then google street view the shit out of it. And double check transit times. And nervously play with my hair for an hour before convincing myself out of going.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Same thing goes for doing days worth of design research on something I should’ve just jumped into and kicked around. Having a little bit of research to nudge a designer along in a certain direction is great, but it’s much better to just jump into something and figure out the right solution than spend time researching what the right solution may be. Because no one else has solved your problem yet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Towards the end of the trip, I started to let go of looking into every detail to make myself more comfortable with where I was going, how I was getting there, and what I was doing. I forgot to take screenshots of maps to places I was staying and instead relied on my general sense of direction, people (actual real people!), and wayfinding. These days, it’s more commonplace to turn first to the internet to look something up or ask a question when it’s probably quicker just asking in person. It’s ok to feel a little lost, but trust that you’ll find where you need to be.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;3. Be friendly and say hi to just about everyone&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Seriously. We could all just a bit more of this in our everyday lives. Think of your best friend and all the amazing things you’ve done together. Now just imagine all the people you encounter that you could potentially have similar experiences with. Once you start treating everyone as a potential friend and are open, traveling alone doesn’t seem so lonely.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://igcdn-photos-h-a.akamaihd.net/hphotos-ak-xap1/t51.2885-15/1538412_938577112829495_280045765_n.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Ljubljana&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I met some great, friendly people throughout my trip who were able to show my around their city and give me an experience I probably wouldn’t have been able to have on my own.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But don’t stop there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s really easy to get sucked back into the old ways of being so closed off in DC. Traveling alone helps me break free of that, speak my mind and realize I have a ton of interests other than just work and traveling. Every time I travel, I always try to bring a little bit more friendliness and openness back with me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One caveat though, always be a little bit cautious and make sure you’re staying safe. Just because you’re traveling to a different city doesn’t mean you can just go wild. The same sort of city rules apply.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;4. Learn to just be&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Be alone. Be present. Be an actual human being instead of a robot tied to a phone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My first night in Dubrovnik went something a little like this:
Holy crap this is an awesome place to stay, hell yes bathrobes. &lt;em&gt;Pats self on back and gets ready for bed.&lt;/em&gt; Now just to plug in my phon— Well, damn. Forgot my adapter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the first half of the trip, I went without a phone charger, so I HAD to reserved the battery for picture-taking instead of wasting it all on twitter, meerkat, or whatever everyone was into during that time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://igcdn-photos-a-a.akamaihd.net/hphotos-ak-xpf1/t51.2885-15/10808621_486050114876248_1907485950_n.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Plitvice National Park&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This has also been the second solo trip I decided not to get a sim card for my phone in order to use it on local cell networks. That meant no google maps, foursquare, etc. outside of any wifi networks. The longer I stopped looking at my phone, the less I kept reaching for it, instead just taking in the sights for as long as I wanted.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not being surrounded by friends, in real life or virtually, most of the time also meant a lot of alone time. Just me. Chilling with my thoughts about life and things. I finished the one book I brought three days into my trip and spent most of my four hour bus ride from Dubrovnik to Split staring out the window at the gorgeous coastline and riveria. Not for one second would I have traded that for seeing someone’s tweet or reading a book.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://igcdn-photos-d-a.akamaihd.net/hphotos-ak-xaf1/t51.2885-15/11084856_867417309971923_497227918_n.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Ljubljana&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</summary>
      <id>//a-designers-perspective-on-solo-travel.html</id>
      <updated>2015-04-02T09:57:51-07:00</updated>
      <author>
        <name>Klare Frank</name>
      </author>
    </entry>
  
    <entry>
      <title>Guest Post — Balancing Work and Home is Key</title>
      <link href="//work-life-balance.html" />
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;I see a lot of my peers in situations that lead them to long hours at work, working on weekends, and taking naps at work. At some companies, this behavior is encouraged and seen as a sign of dedication. At others (&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.washingtonpost.com/local/at-some-start-ups-fridays-are-so-casual-everyone-can-stay-home/2015/02/06/31e8407e-9d1c-11e4-96cc-e858eba91ced_story.html&quot;&gt;such as I the one I work at&lt;/a&gt;), time outside of work is valued to prevent burnout and promote smarter work. &lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;My mother, Louisa Frank, taught herself how to program in the early ‘80s and has been an inspiration for me working in technology. She later moved into a leadership role in the technology department at a large bank, managing a whole team of project managers and developers. Even though we’re a generation apart and she was in the banking industry, not a startup culture, I can see a lot of parallels between our experiences, especially when it comes to companies promoting a culture of being always available for work.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;Her takeaway? It’s the experiences and people that matter. You’re probably not going to remember that deadline you may have missed by an hour if you had’t stayed up late, but you will remember a missed opportunity to spend with family or friends.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;Spread the love where it counts.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Some of us are aware that there is nothing more important than family, but many people cannot balance their home life and work life appropriately. Not everyone knows that home is as important, if not more, than work. I heard, once, that you should think about what you want written on your tombstone when you die. Will it say that you lived your life loving your family or that you lived your life at work, hardly ever seeing your family? Balance is important. I’ve seen more than one marriage fall apart because the individual cannot maintain a good balance in and out of the office.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was lucky. I have a very understanding spouse and kids that are proud of me and support me, as well. Not everyone is so blessed. However, even with a supportive family, I had to work hard at a balance between work and home. Did I achieve it? I’ll be the first to admit that I didn’t, but I wasn’t too far off balance, even with the long hours I put in at the office. There are a few times that I regretted not being able to drop everything and rush home, but it worked out, in the end.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I hired people, I told them, up front, that everyone often had to work overtime to support technical issues, bring in a project on time, or complete new installations and updates. Most times overtime could be planned ahead. For instance, if we were doing an install of new software, we would know this ahead of time and be able to predict when we’d be spending more hours at work than at home. What couldn’t be accounted for were those emergencies that popped up, and they were numerous, and they sucked at our personal time like a vampire sucks blood from his victim.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a manager, it is important to be aware of how much time your people spend at work, or working. It is so simple to become burned out by working too much, and so easy to see family life fall apart. Everyone is different in how much balance they need, but it is not only up to you, as an individual, to ensure you are getting it, but up to you, as a manager, to be aware if your people are balancing properly. Balance keeps everyone happy, and in top mental shape to perform at work. Happy people help projects come in on time and budget.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a woman, with children, I think I was able to sympathize with many of my people when they needed time at home. I also think I had more awareness of the balance between work and family, not only for my own situation, but for my people, too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In order to balance my work and home life, I often planned vacations away, with my husband and kids. That’s something I enjoyed, but we also spent quality time at home playing games, swimming, cooking, watching television, and other things. I remember well standing, soaking wet in my swim suit, on the phone at a Disney water park, and sitting on a bench outside of the Haunted Mansion, again, on the phone. I was contacted to get on production support issues. While my husband and the kids had a blast, I put in my time on the phone helping get the issue fixed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Why not make it a rule to never contact people while on vacation? I thought of that rule. For my own team, when one of my developers went on vacation, I made sure he left his pager (yeah, we had pagers back then) at the office. If it was a dire emergency, I knew how to get in touch with him, but otherwise, no one else was allowed to bother him, or her, while they were away. Now-a-days, everyone has a mobile phone, so it is easy to contact someone. Texting is a way of life. If I were out in the workforce, now, I’d tell my people to ignore all calls/texts from anyone except me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Having that precious, uninterrupted time spent with your spouse, friend, or family is important for that balance. Not getting it can quickly lead to burnout. Does it hurt not to be able to contact the one person that might get the issue solved quickly? You bet! But in the long run, it makes others more self-sufficient, forcing them to learn the software and how to fix it, and it helped me to learn, as a manager, the capabilities of my people.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another time, I was on a call, on and off, throughout the night and into the morning. I was behind closed doors in my home office, but I had the phone on speaker with the volume low so as not to disturb anyone else. My parents were, at the time, temporarily living in my basement, having decided to move back near their children and grandchildren after retirement. I thought everyone was asleep. Imagine my surprise when my father strode into my office, wearing only his underwear. He stomped right up to my desk and stood over the phone and said something like,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“You quit that damn job!”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He then calmly left the room. Since I was on speaker, everyone on the call heard him. There was silence on the other end of the line. No one spoke for almost a whole minute then someone, I don’t know who, diffused the situation by saying something funny, but I could tell everyone on the call was thinking the same thing as me: “What the heck am I doing?” It made me review my work/home balance to make sure I wasn’t going overboard. I stepped back a bit, after that incident.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I said I had an understanding spouse and kids that supported me. Really, though, my kids knew my office at work inside and out because they spent a lot of time there. Often, on the weekends, they went in to the office with me. It was their home away from home. They knew the vending machine selections by heart. It also gave them time to get to know my developers and my bosses and it gave me time with the kids, even though I was working. My developer’s kids spent time in the office, too, so it was not uncommon. I remember someone’s kid riding their tricycle around and around the office cubes while we worked.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(Those connections that my kids made when they were young, visiting my office were put to use later on to their benefit. My son scored a summer job when he was in college, working with another team at my company, which lead, eventually, to a full time job in the technology world when he finished college. My daughter used her work connections to get a recommendation from one of my very senior bosses to the college of her choice. She met that super senior boss at a wedding we were invited to when she was younger, and, when it came time to apply to colleges, he remembered her.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Did I quit that damn job? In actuality, I quit five times over the thirteen years I worked there, but every time I quit, someone talked me out of it. When I quit for the final time, number six, it was for real. At that time, the company had totally changed. If it hadn’t, I’d probably still be there. I have never regretted that final decision.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Maybe I should have quit that job sooner. I ended up making a lot of money, enough to take the whole family wherever we wanted on vacation each year. We didn’t want for lack of funds. That was for sure, and I got to treat my family to all sorts of new adventures that I wouldn’t want to trade for anything, but was it worth it to have to spend all that time away from them? I’ll never know. I’m still married, and my kids have grown and started their own careers, and I have regrets that I didn’t spend enough time with them, but I think I did the best I could in balancing my career and my home life. It was important to me back then, and it is still important to me. It should be important to everyone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;OK. So what am I getting at? Do you need to spend hours and hours at work to get ahead? No. You need to create a good balance between your work life and your home life so that you are satisfied you are doing the best you can with both. You must also use your after hours work time wisely and get the most out of it. Be aware of your balance and work at keeping it healthy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I learned many lessons in my long career in technology, climbing the ladder rung by rung to the executive level. I used those lessons wisely, and, even today, still use them. I also include them in all my books. They are still relevant, no matter what the job. I’ve changed careers from being a technology executive to working at becoming a writer, yet my past lessons still come into play for me. Even though I’m older and there’s a new generation out there in the working world, it’s surprising how so much changes, but so much stays the same.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;


&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;Louisa Frank is a retired Senior Vice President of Technology at Bank of America. A few years ago, she retired early and revisited her programming roots, amongst other things, learning HTML and CSS, programming and maintaining a website for a non-profit firm and her own website, &lt;a href=&quot;http://thisislafrank.com&quot;&gt;thisislafrank.com&lt;/a&gt;, in addition to writing. You can contact her at her website or at &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:thisislafrank@gmail.com&quot;&gt;thisislafrank@gmail.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</summary>
      <id>//work-life-balance.html</id>
      <updated>2015-03-03T08:57:51-08:00</updated>
      <author>
        <name>Klare Frank</name>
      </author>
    </entry>
  
    <entry>
      <title>Getting Started</title>
      <link href="//getting-started.html" />
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;About two months ago, I decided to take up running. As with anything I try to master, I gave it a scoff with slight arrogance, exclaiming, “So and so did it and is great at it, so why can’t I?!” In this case, it was my high-school aged cousin, Kevin, who continually wins state-wide cross country races while silently chanting Invictus.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So as my friends started a wittily named run club (“Two Quads, One Squad”) to train for a half marathon, I decided to join to see how good I could get at this thing. Since I had never been great at athletics growing up, save for a short stint on a soccer team and in a gymnastics league until I broke my arm in fourth grade, I had low expectations. My one goal: just to get out there and see how far I could go.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And yet, even that proved to be difficult.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There’s a tipping point, I learned, between when I could force my butt out the door or have my running shoes propped up, lamenting how I’m absolutely terrible at this thing and subscribing to the continual beat down that logically stemmed from the lack of practice and illogically grew from my bruised ego. In the latter, I’d be battling the forces of ‘I can’t’ for the rest of the day. In the former, I’d be liberated to squash great tasks that day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Simply put, the longer I thought about going for a run, the more difficult it became and I was less likely to go and do it. (Perhaps why Nike’s famous tagline is so aptly phrased.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;“I’m never going to be good anyway.”&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In college, perfectionist procrastination got me in big trouble when I decided there was no way my concept for cyanotypes was good enough and I failed my alternative photographic processes class. I had one last project to redeem my grade, a photo transfer project, but I also waited too long on that one too. When I arrived at the photo studio, all the supplies had already been used by my classmates and I was left to my own devices. Let me tell you, using gel medium to transfer photos onto canvas does not work and all you’ll end up with is what resembles a child’s attempt at making their own paper from scratch. So after cursing photography (and getting back into making websites a few months later as a creative outlet), I decided that any crappy work I could produce, anything that I at least tried at, was better than delivering nothing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Truthfully, I spend a hell of a lot of time thinking about the proper order to do things before getting started—more than I should. I still spend a lot of time researching and sketching before getting into design. It roughly ends up being two-thirds preparation and one-third actual work. That’s not to say preparation isn’t important, but sometimes I use it as a crutch to soak and squeeze the most information out of a project when I should just be starting. You have to recognize the point when to start and force yourself on that path immediately when you know.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;“You won’t have enough time, just do it tomorrow.”&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If I end up forcing myself out to go running before I’ve reached the tipping point, the scenario usually goes something like this: &lt;em&gt;oh god—oh god—oh god—I’m going to die—just make it halfway—you’re almost there—oh god—why did I ever decided to do this—I’m going to die—ok just make it home—you’re nearly there—you can see it—oh hey this isn’t too bad—I think I could probably run another mile—good job Klare—that wasn’t too bad—I didn’t die—let’s go again tomorrow—ok that kinda felt good.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The worst part is I know the longer I try to convince myself I won’t have enough time, the less time I’ll actually have and it’ll become a self-fulfilling prophecy of nonsense. This is why identifying the tipping point is crucial, because once I start any project or activity, it becomes easier to complete as I see the end on the horizon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;“Everyone will know you’re a beginner and pity you.”&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Something about starting always terrifies me. It’s like when you go to your first Rocky Horror show and they put a red ‘V’ on your forehead with bright red lipstick. Yeah, that’s what it feels like every time I want to try something new and know I’m going to be terrible at it. Cue falling down and tumbling over myself and calling it progress. I didn’t want to be that person that goes out and buys all the best gear ever and has Photoshop CS Infinity only to use filters and lens flares worse than teenagers on Instagram.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yet, when I see a beginner or someone new to the community, all I want to do is encourage their success. This new person chose to explore something I know I love and I actually get giddy knowing she has a chance to experience the same joy I have. It’s the same with people learning frontend development, even if they aren’t as excited about it. I’ll gladly offer my time and support to help them learn because I know one of the best feelings is the aha moment of development when you create something with determination and it actually works. Pity belongs nowhere in those feelings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Starting is sometimes the hardest part. For me, I’ve learned that knowing my weaknesses and limitations helps to craft tactics to lessen them. Sometimes it means not waiting to let my mind trick myself into thinking I can’t. Sometimes it just requires womaning up and getting things done. However, nothing is more effective than convincing myself that I can finish, whether it’s three miles or launching a website or deciding my dreams are worthy enough to try.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;It matters not how strait the gate,&lt;br&gt;
How charge with punishments the scroll, &lt;br&gt;
I am the master of my fate,&lt;br&gt;
I am the captain of my soul.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br&gt;
— William Ernest Henley&lt;/p&gt;
</summary>
      <id>//getting-started.html</id>
      <updated>2015-02-18T08:57:51-08:00</updated>
      <author>
        <name>Klare Frank</name>
      </author>
    </entry>
  
    <entry>
      <title>Why I decided to learn how to program – a recollection from my mother</title>
      <link href="//why-i-decided-to-learn-to-program.html" />
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;My mother, Louisa Frank, taught herself how to program in the early ‘80s and has been an inspiration for me also learning how to code. I constantly remind myself that if she could do it, so can I. She’s been a fantastic example of a successful woman in our industry — in both programming AND leadership. I’ve asked her to share some of her experiences throughout her career in technology.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;


&lt;p&gt;I stumbled onto computers quite by accident. I needed a job to help pay for college, and the campus newspaper advertised an opening for a typist. This was in the early ‘80s, when typewriters were still common. I had no idea what the job entailed, but I knew how to type, rather slowly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I took one typing course, a filler course, in high school. Telling me that typing was a skill that any girl needed to learn, my parents encouraged me to take the course. While it was mostly girls, there were a handful of boys in my class. They signed up for the class so that they could watch the teacher for a whole period. She was young, fresh out of school, and pretty, and she flirted with all the boys in the class and they lapped up her attention.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“A,S,D,F,L,K,J,H,” she would shout as all the students dutifully pressed the appropriate key, clacking away in unison.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Later, I used my typing skill to complete my writing assignments for high school and then for college. My electronic typewriter that I’d received for Christmas went with me when I moved into my first dorm, much as a laptop or tablet computer goes with most students today.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;School was expensive, and to help pay the bills, I searched for a part-time job, preferably on campus, so that I could juggle my class time and work time. This was how I spotted the advertisement. My room mate encourage me to go see about it. I fretted that I couldn’t type that quickly and made frequent use of correction tape to fix my mistakes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“So what?” she said. “Go and find out about it. Maybe they won’t make you take a typing test. Maybe they don’t care how fast you can type or how accurately. You never know until you ask. That’s how I got my job.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;She worked in the library, filing returned books. She knew nothing about library science, but had applied, anyway.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The department advertising the job was located in a little brick house with a wide front porch that I later found out was used as an extra conference room. When I walked in the door, I was surprised to see large, upright boxes on long tables lining the former living room and dining room of the converted residence. In front of each box was a chair, and people sat in those chairs looking intently onto the front of the boxes, or typing on the keyboards resting on the tables. Those “boxes” turned out to be computer terminals, and the people were actually looking at graphical displays on their screens.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“When can you start? Today?” the man named Keith asked me when I told him I was inquiring about the job. He didn’t ask me how many words a minute I could type, or even want to know if I was any good. He was so desperate for someone to fill the position, anyone willing to do the work was fine with him.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Keith sat me down at one of the terminals and explained my new position. I would be entering questions into a database. When students wanted to practice taking the C.P.A. exam, they could run a program which would randomly pull these questions from storage and display them on the screen. The student could then input the answer and find out their score when they finished.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I must have typed thousands of questions into the computer, but the more I typed, the more I became fascinated about the computer, the program the students used to take the practice exam, and the database that held the questions. I asked question after question of Keith.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“How does the computer know which question to get from the database?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“How does the program work?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“How does it the computer know to light up one little spot here and not over there?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And on and on. I knew almost nothing about computers. I had a calculator that could do math, but that was about it. I didn’t have any courses that required computers and computer science was a brand new major at the university, exclusive and difficult to get into. Those that majored in computer science used the very large Burroughs computer that required punched cards. Or, computer science students sat down at a terminal, a large device that had a keyboard in front and a ream of paper fed into the back, somewhat like an overlarge typewriter on a stand. Commands were entered by the user, onto the keyboard just like a typewriter, and printed on the paper in the back. When a program was compiled, the computer took over and printed the result onto the paper. (I’d used this type of terminal in high school when my physics teacher let me and a few other students play games on it in the lab during our free period.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Keith showed me the program behind the practice C.P.A. exam and I was surprised how easy it was to read. I started learning all I could about the programming language and the other applications that ran on this computer. This was not the powerful Burroughs computer that the computer science majors used. This was totally different. It was a CDC computer running what was called PLATO (Programmed Logic for Automated Teaching Operations). Housing several thousand instructional programs and displaying them on graphics terminals worldwide, it used a language called TUTOR, with commands written in English, programs compiled, and displayed on the screen, not punched on a card and fed into the machine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I thought it looked easy to write a program, and I was very interested in the how behind the ones I saw running on the screens, so I decided I was going to write my own. I thought up the subject, Architectural Drawing. I was very much into drafting because I was an engineering major. I would try to write an instructional programming that taught simple concepts of drafting. I borrowed a book on TUTOR and I got started all on my own.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A graphical program, my Architectural Drawing application drew drafting plans on the screen via my programming commands, provided instructions to the user, then displayed a question/answer quiz at the end. It took the student step-by-step through the process of making an accurate draft of a simple building.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I was done with my program, and very proud of it, I showed it to by boss, Keith.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He took one look at it and exclaimed,“You, my dear, are no longer a typist. You are a computer programmer!”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From that day forward, I stopped typing C.P.A. questions into the computer. I was assigned to create instructional applications, instead. I learned how to use a database to hold my graphics and display them quickly, drawing cartoon characters, accounting graphs, and guidance principles on the screen, in addition to instructions for the user. I loved it! I was hooked.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was also very lucky to have Keith for a boss and to have started my programming career on the CDC computer. Keith very much fostered learning and encouraged me. He guided me by making suggestions on what to research and how to fix bugs, for instance. He gave me one-on-one instruction, something I never would have received had I been a student in the Computer Science department. Keith taught me that I could do almost anything I wanted, including computer programming.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I knew, after that first program, what I wanted to do for a career. I wanted to be a programmer. There was a satisfaction, after a long day sitting in front of a terminal, programming, compiling, and debugging, to see the results of my labor up on the screen. I’m artistic by nature, and programming let my creative side go wild. Writing a program was not only figuring out the commands needed and putting them in the right sequence, it was giving me creative license to develop my application, from start to finish, begin to end (the first and last commands of the program), in the way I saw fit to achieve the desired result on the screen. It was like putting together a puzzle, figuring out which pieces connected to which, finding all the corners and edge pieces and filling in the middle, tossing out one piece in favor of another, until, at the end, the whole puzzle came together to form a perfectly running, bug-free application.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve seen code that looks like a work of art, in itself, with all the commands lined up just so, and indented likewise. I’ve seen code that looks like a hurricane passed through. Each person has their own signature they depart upon their own code, their own artistic signature, good or bad. Good companies allow their software developers to use their own style, to a point. It helps keep the developer happy, and often gets results much quicker than if they must conform to rigid standards. It also keeps the developer thinking creatively about how to complete that assignment, how to get what the client wants up on the screen in the most efficient, most economical, but most beneficial way, and how to fix production problems quickly and creatively when each minute that ticks by means thousands of dollars lost to the company.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I went on to write many more programs in my first position at the university, then was hired full time. Once I graduated, I continued to work for this department at the university for a few more years before moving on and up in my career working with software.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;


&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;Louisa Frank is a retired Senior Vice President of Technology at Bank of America. After starting her career at the University of Delaware Plato Project, she went on to work in several major companies, progressing from software developer to software team leader, software manager, and finally technology executive. A few years ago, she retired early and revisited her programming roots, amongst other things, learning HTML and CSS, programming and maintaining a website for a non-profit firm, Water Is Life Kenya, and maintaining her own website, &lt;a href=&quot;http://thisislafrank.com&quot;&gt;thisislafrank.com&lt;/a&gt;. You can contact her at her website or at &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:thisislafrank@gmail.com&quot;&gt;thisislafrank@gmail.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</summary>
      <id>//why-i-decided-to-learn-to-program.html</id>
      <updated>2015-01-12T08:57:51-08:00</updated>
      <author>
        <name>Klare Frank</name>
      </author>
    </entry>
  
    <entry>
      <title>Lessons and Resolutions</title>
      <link href="//lessons-and-resolutions.html" />
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I don’t make resolutions. Ever since sixth grade when we had to write our new years resolutions on sheets of colored construction paper to hang up in the hallway, I’ve always thought of them as an opportunity for disappointment. I think I came up with something vague like ‘be better’. Seriously. I was kinda a hipster kid who hated boy bands and thought being like everyone else was the worst thing ever.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I still have never made a new years resolution. Sure, I’ve had goals and dreams, but I’ve always tried never to put a definite time on them and assume that the right time will come around. If it doesn’t, I’ll probably be too annoyed with myself and make it happen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This year I decided to choose something every month to focus on. Once that month was done, I’d either have forgotten what I was doing or evaluate, pick a new goal, and move on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s a few of the things I focused on in 2014:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Be an active listener&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sometimes I have this simultaneous conversation in my head every time I meet someone for the first time. It usually goes like: What am I going to say next? What can I come up with to make them think I’m interesting. Avoid awkward pauses. Cmon. Aww shit. You just forgot their name.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Icebreakers are fine when you first meet someone, but the best conversations just happen naturally out of mentioning the randomest things. To do that, you have to actually listen to the conversation and not try to act some play or figure our what’s next. It’ll come naturally if you’re paying attention and are actually interested. If not, count it as an off day and move on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Spend time away from a screen&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I gave up Netflix in 2014, save for a brief two days in February obviously reserved for a House of Cards marathon, which forced me to read books for entertainment whenever I was home. I was rarely ever home, but I did manage to finish a good dozen of books this year. I also realized that tv shows come up a LOT in normal conversation, which most of the time made me feel like a strange time traveler with a blank look on my face. I also brewed more beers this year than last and spent more time on a plane than probably in the past five years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Stress less&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I know when I’m stressed out because I wake up with an aching jaw or find myself clenching my teeth in the middle of the day. Which I didn’t really think was that big a problem until my dentist told me I had partially fractured a molar. Seriously. Stress is bad for your health. Find ways to get past it, whether it’s removing yourself from a situation, talking it out, or meditating.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Make exercise a habit&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Growing up, I never ran under a ten minute mile. Despite not being overweight, I always dreaded gym class. I think it’s one of those things where you try something once and think you’re not good at it so you decide you’re not athletic (or artistic) and have a self-assigned label plastered on you all your life. But kids are rarely told you can still be great at something even if you suck the first time. So I stuck to individual sports, like biking.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In my adult life, I’ve never really had that much luck making it a habit, but after working at a desk for years and having to deal with some moderate scoliosis, I really wanted to build up better posture (or as better as I can).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Drink less alcohol, drink more water&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This was a tough one, since DC is very much a social drinking city and I made Monday night happy hours a thing. Also since I brew beer. But, damn, there’s only so much drinking a person can do in one day before they decide it’s time to just grow up. Bye bye all day epic brunches. It’s for the best.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Go your own way&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This year I made my first solo trip to Europe. Barcelona, specifically. It’s a great way to build confidence, especially in a city where I didn’t know either of the languages. (I studied German in high school and college, not Spanish like most people in America.) There’s things I used to get shy about, like talking to strangers or going out to eat by myself. On a solo trip, you have to get over those fears pretty quickly otherwise you’re going to be hungry and miss out on meeting some great people.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now if I need to do something I’ve never done before, I assume since I could navigate a foreign city and make it back home in one piece, it won’t be too bad. I recently booked my second solo trip for a longer duration.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Work on something that matters&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I mostly decided to become a Developer in Residence at General Assembly this year because I had always been interested in education and mentoring. After seeing a good friend go from learning almost no html and css to getting a second job as a frontend dev in two years, I realized there’s nothing more amazing than that first aha moment someone has when learning how to be a developer. This year, it’s most all of my work as been about education or providing opportunities, especially since I switched jobs to join the team at Treehouse. I’m really grateful that I never have to question the morality of what I create.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s been a great year and I’ve learned a hell of a lot about myself. Honestly, I’m probably the most confident I’ve been in years and can’t wait to show all of you want I’m working on and planning for next year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks &amp;amp; Happy New Year.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary>
      <id>//lessons-and-resolutions.html</id>
      <updated>2014-12-31T07:16:21-08:00</updated>
      <author>
        <name>Klare Frank</name>
      </author>
    </entry>
  
    <entry>
      <title>Switching to Vim</title>
      <link href="//switching-to-vim.html" />
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The first time I started using vim, it was more a necessity than by choice. It was a little bit too late for me to walk to work one morning and still make my morning meeting, so I did what I always did, rode my bike. Not even ten seconds after I had mounted and pushed away from my apartment building, my pedal collided with the oh so lovely marble curbs of dc and I was suddenly flying over my handlebars on one of the busiest streets in the morning. It could’ve been worse. I only ended up with a minor scrape on my leg, but the brunt of my fall had been stopped by my dominant hand. Riding the rest of the way to work that morning, I could barely squeeze the breaks properly and knew I had to lay off it for a few days in order for my hand to have a chance to heal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Designing with one hand is a challenge. It’s nearly impossible to do in Photoshop or Sketch, which both require complicated multi-keyed commands to execute even the most basic tasks. Just try drawing a rectangle with one hand on a trackpad. It doesn’t really work. Switching to a mouse didn’t even occur to me. I had been using a trackpad ever since my sophomore year of college when I used to play some pretty intense World of Warcraft on a MacBook Pro.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had heard about vim being great for only using keyboard commands, and ditching a trackpad meant one less thing for me to worry about. Everyone who had successfuly switched over to vim praised how much faster it could be. I didn’t have much to lose and at least I knew I could type with one hand, so I decided to try it out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Tips for Switching to Vim&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Don’t expect to be that quick starting out. Hell. I was a lot slower. There’s a ton of commands you need to memorize, just like with any design program, and they’re probably not ones you’re familiar with. &lt;a href=&quot;http://cheetyr.com/vim&quot;&gt;Vim Cheetyr&lt;/a&gt; helps a ton. Just have that open all the time.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Start with small commands, and when you find yourself doing something a lot slower than in Sublime Text, look up a shortcut. There’s always a shortcut.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Learn how to set up a .vimrc file. Setting up your preferences (especially syntax highlighting) helps tremendously.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Don’t expect to code the same way as you did in Sublime Text. This isn’t like upgrading a version. Expect that everything is different and, again, always question if you can be doing something quicker.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;


&lt;h2&gt;Things I’ve learned&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;It’s a hell of a lot easier to use vim with one hand than sublime text, sketch, or photoshop.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;It takes practice, but eventually it is way faster.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Github merge messages seem a hell of a lot less scary. And you know the commands to quit properly instead of panicing and quitting terminal.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;It helps a lot with focusing on one task, especially since it’s a lot easier to work in one file at a time.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;It makes you feel like you’re in a secret club that’s visible to everyone but they don’t understand how awesome it is.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;


&lt;p&gt;It’s been a few months since I first tried vim out, but overall, I’m enjoying it a lot more. With everything, it takes a bit of practice to learn, but it makes me feel like I’m driving a manual over an automatic; I’m just closer to the code. And, if I ever sprain my hand again, I’ll know I can still get things done.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary>
      <id>//switching-to-vim.html</id>
      <updated>2014-12-23T04:34:51-08:00</updated>
      <author>
        <name>Klare Frank</name>
      </author>
    </entry>
  
    <entry>
      <title>How the UX Designer killed Design</title>
      <link href="//how-the-ux-designer-killed-design.html" />
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;It’s the same question that comes up during every interview: “If you could choose between only designing and only coding, which would it be?” The first time I was asked that, it caught me off guard, mostly because I hadn’t experienced one separate from the other.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To a young and naive me, coding was what my Dad did in his home office with five terminal windows open. It reminded me of when he worked in an actual office and there was a warm, humming server room with wires everywhere making tangled nests behind the server racks. It was a mystical place where I didn’t know what those big, tall racks did, or how someone could manipulate real, physical things to make connected systems work. I definitely didn’t do that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Design was something that people graduated from school with a degree in where they put together their final book project and gushed over typefaces. Fonts designed for screens were barely available when I was first looking for a job and while I knew what proper spacing was and could call myself a designer, I definitely knew nothing about print. I didn’t have a degree in it. That single, lacking, piece of paper fueled my imposter syndrome for years following. I still can’t call line-height leading when I’m not looking at type on a screen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Early on, even before I knew that graduating with a degree in Global Studies would yield nothing more than having a comprehensive understanding of countries on a map, my idols were the ones creating the web. They were the ones pushing for better type rendering on screens, responsive design, more whitespace, easier organization of frontend code, and simplifying web experiences. In my mind, these were all the same people and if I was ever going to be a great designer who also influenced the future of the web, I needed to be doing all these things.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So when the question was posed to me, I said neither. Without one or the other, I would easily become bored and uninterested, probably lamenting the loss of using skills I enjoyed using every day. Being a designer who practiced neither user experience design nor frontend development meant I was potentially crippling myself from being a master in the craft.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Despite that, visual design has consistently been my most challenging aspect of design. It’s taken a while to get to a point where I could illustrate anything I thought was of decent quality. I’ve nearly (and probably) cried over designs that weren’t coming together and sometimes wished I would’ve had an education from a design school because maybe it would’ve made things easier. Yet, I’ve always stuck with it and pushed through the muck to chisel out something I can be somewhat proud of.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;A Fork in the Road&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I’m in the midst of transitioning jobs, I’ve been dwelling upon the few pivotal opportunities where I could’ve chosen to do only user experience design. It would’ve set me down a track based solely on facts, research, and testing. And while those are all necessary parts of design, I never did choose that path.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;Choosing to specialize and be a user experience designer simply felt like giving up.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even when I was placed on teams and titled the ‘visual designer’ and paired with user experience designers and frontend developers, I tried to never be complacent in my role, always choosing constant collaboration over strict role delegation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And maybe that’s because I’ve always felt a visual designer is more than colors and type and spacing and how things &lt;em&gt;feel&lt;/em&gt;. It’s a balance of the analytic and the aesthetic. To be the best designer I can, it takes a strong understanding of how the web works, the trends (good or bad), and the best practices.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Siloing is for suckers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;A Visual Designer is a UX Designer is a Designer&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;User experience design doesn’t stop at gray boxes; it extends to how a user responds to a page, and that includes how it looks as well as how it functions. It’s more than making a site ‘look pretty’ or coloring in boxes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s one of the reasons the chart from &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.uxisnotui.com/downloads/without-title.png&quot;&gt;uxisnotui.com&lt;/a&gt; became so popular. While it’s important to help people understand all the different aspects that make up creating a user experience, somehow the column titled “How UX Wants to be Seen” got replaced with “UX Designers” and the column “How UX is Typically Seen” replaced with “Visual Designers”, making it more of a role delegation than a comprehensive list of all the things designers do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mark Boulton describes this perfectly in his article &lt;a href=&quot;https://themanual.org/read/issues/2/mark-boulton/article&quot;&gt;Visual Design is Not a Thing&lt;/a&gt;. In it, he talks about the industry’s response to Jesse James Garrett’s &lt;em&gt;The Elements of User Experience&lt;/em&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“This attitude was unfortunately reinforced by the recent rise in the opinion that user experience design—not graphic design—was the definition of good web design. … According to the industry’s perception of this model, what designers don’t do on the surface plane is design; they decorate.”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Somewhere along the way, the collective makers of the web realized the importance of ux (yay!) while neglected advocating for visual design—the cast aside casualty. Instead of judging the quality of a website as a whole, user experience design became the most important factor. Yet, a users judge of a website’s credibility does not stop before visual design. If a website has a great experience and still looks horrible, users will still be confused. Prentice Mathew &lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/@prenticemathew/ux-specialists-are-killing-web-design-50b7d7607c13&quot;&gt;observed this&lt;/a&gt; when Gov.uk won the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/entertainment-arts-22164715&quot;&gt;“Design of the year award”&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“Visual Design is still the most important pillar which supports the UX (don’t forget the “X” stands for “Experience”) framework, and most users still evaluate the credibility of a website based solely on it’s visual appeal.”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This attitude is further reflected in the salary difference between &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.coroflot.com/designsalaryguide/user-experience-designer/united-states&quot;&gt;ux designers&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.coroflot.com/designsalaryguide/web-designer/united-states&quot;&gt;web designers&lt;/a&gt;. UX designers are consistently paid more even though visual designers have all the skills they need to know how to be a competent ux designer on top of what they already practice. The placement of a button drives engagement while the overall style affects credibility. The choice of fonts influences the users’ disposition. A lawyer’s website set in comic sans will always prove too unprofessional and negatively accept business.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;User experience processes—such as user testing, research, and creating personas— reinforce (or weaken) these assumptions made in visual design.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;An Even More Collaborative Web&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s clear we can’t neglect visual design. But we also can’t neglect visual designers. A visual or graphic designer who expands her or his understanding of user experience design best practices and process becomes a better designer overall.
A user experience designer who learns about graphic design can better understand how design on the surface influences users. Only when both kinds of designers broaden their knowledge can they collaborate as equals and the unknown seems less mystical and scary.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whether a team is made up of designers and developers in traditional roles or not, user experience design should not just be for ux designers. It should bear equal weight with all of the other roles and processes that make up creating web experiences. A great website comes from a collaborative environment where all disciplines of web creation are treated as equals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For me, that means seeking out and pushing for roles that will let me practice ux and visual design while also doing frontend development. For a team, it means collaborating equally between teammates, regardless of who is working on what.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’re all working towards the same goal and great ideas can come from anywhere.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary>
      <id>//how-the-ux-designer-killed-design.html</id>
      <updated>2014-11-12T07:29:21-08:00</updated>
      <author>
        <name>Klare Frank</name>
      </author>
    </entry>
  
    <entry>
      <title>Designing for Scale</title>
      <link href="//designing-for-scale.html" />
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;This past Saturday, &lt;a href=&quot;http://twitter.com/felskia&quot;&gt;Ali Felski&lt;/a&gt; and I had the pleasure of doing a workshop at the &lt;a href=&quot;http://codeherconference.com/&quot;&gt;Code(Her) Conference&lt;/a&gt;. We went over our process for tackling user experience and user interface design for large web builds and the considerations we take when creating these sites. If you’d like, download our &lt;a href=&quot;/assets/img/blogs/building-for-scale.pdf&quot;&gt;slides&lt;/a&gt; for more information. For more clarification, I thought I’d outline my process for designing interfaces for scale.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Why does it matter?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’ve all been on a project that seems to take a life of it’s own and morph into something unrecognizable. Projects like this soon have no clear goals and are like buildings that keep being built on top of buildings. Team members change over time, features may change over time, but design direction should stay solid throughout all this change. Designing for scale is about predicting the future of a site that’ll live on after the team is done initially building and designing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Three goals for designing for scale&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;1. Flexibility&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On larger projects, things can change rapidly. Since there are more moving parts, one change from a client could potentially mean a rework of an entire part of the site. Building a website as a system usually prevents headaches associated with these problems.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;2. Consistency&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Components that act the same will look similar across all pages so websites stay on brand and don’t confuse users.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;3. Speed&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If a new feature is discovered from user testing as being of prime importance and needs to be built right away, styles already exist to do so.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Dynamic Content&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is a consideration that’s paramount when designing static comps, and one which will most likely arise as a design problem when designing in-browser. In either situation, it’s inevitable that content will be both too short and too long.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Developers usually compensate for this by either limiting characters on input or cutting off text after a certain number of characters using an elipsis.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We can do better than that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By asking “what if?” while designing, it’s easier to add the correct solutions for little or lots of text.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Styleguide-driven design&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A lot of people talk about developing based off generated styles that keep consistency of visual direction throughout a website, but no one really talks about how a designer starts from functionality and gets to the point of enough designed user interface to have a complete styleguide.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Clients love to think in terms of pages and deliverables. Developers love reusable components and not pages. Users don’t care beyond the homepage as long as they can accomplish a task. As a designer, I need to find a compromise between presentation and creating a system that’ll grow after I’m finished with it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Process, not tools&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It doesn’t matter what you use to do the work. There’ll never be a magical tool that’ll do the work for you. Use the tools you’re comfortable in (or not, if you so choose), work best with your team, and help you create the best work possible. What works for me, might not work for you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Taking inventory&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This could take a while.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I start by going through every wireframe and listing out all the components by labeling them as a css class. At ISL, we’re using &lt;a href=&quot;http://bem.info/method/&quot;&gt;BEM methodology&lt;/a&gt; for our css structure, so I usually list them this way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Additionally, I screenshot all these common elements and throw them into a Sketch file for later. It helps having a visual example for each component in addition to just listing them out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Static approach&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Typically created using Sketch because of it’s ability to link symbols. This is where that file full of screenshots comes in handy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I like to start out designing a few important pages. These pages get shown to the client so we know we’re headed in the right direction. Then the components on these pages are turned into symbols and can be used on other pages. There’s a significant back and forth here where symbols get slightly updated to become more flexible over a greater amount of pages. I also think it helps to continually look at all the pages being designed holistically to make sure everything is headed in the same design direction.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the Sketch file, make sure there’s a page with all the symbols that’ll act as the base for the styleguide. Developers will love you forever for making this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not every page will be designed as a static comp. We’re aiming for the pages with the most reused components. Design just enough so it can be translated to code as soon as possible. Type looks different in photoshop, sketch, and illustrator. Elements look different at different browser sizes. There’s no replacement for evaluating a design in it’s intended medium.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Inbrowser approach&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(This is my preferred approach, but if I’m working with designers who don’t know code, it may not be the approach chosen.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I start by laying out a base style with color, typography, form inputs, etc. Everything including in this base style is extremely similar to what Brad Frost outlines as atoms in &lt;a href=&quot;http://pattern-lab.info&quot;&gt;Pattern Lab&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After this, I can start designing components, every so often switching between pages that share those components to see how well they integrate. You can’t just design all components on their own and expect a great site. Sure, it’ll be flexible, but most likely, the ui will look pieced together. We don’t want that. We’re aiming for great, not passable. During this phase, there will be a lot of back and forth where components influence pages and pages influence components. Focus on the little details and then step back every once and a while to look at the whole thing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As components are added and change, they’re linked to a styleguide that also changes. Any designer or developer can pull from that styleguide to keep consistency.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Evaluate &amp;amp; Iterate&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nothing’s ever 100% right the first go around. Know this and plan for it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A large site doesn’t stop when the project ends, it keeps on living and evolving far after all the papers have been signed and the checks delivered.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary>
      <id>//designing-for-scale.html</id>
      <updated>2014-09-15T03:29:21-07:00</updated>
      <author>
        <name>Klare Frank</name>
      </author>
    </entry>
  
    <entry>
      <title>BeardSwipe</title>
      <link href="//beardswipe.html" />
      <summary type="html">&lt;div class=&quot;hero&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;embed-container&quot;&gt;&lt;iframe src=&quot;http://player.vimeo.com/video/90373042&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;allowfullscreen&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;div class=&quot;content--post&quot;&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;What We Built&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We put together a full experience, including a social media campaign, website and app design, and a promo video to ensure the prank was fully believable. Users arrived at a striking single-page website (that purposefully mimicked the style of trendy startup websites) to view the full offering of the BeardSwipe app. The site drove users to a marketing video, featuring many of our bearded and not-so-bearded team members. When users clicked the &#39;Download The App&#39; button they were taken to the iStrategyLabs website and informed that they had been pranked.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the most interesting aspects of our team composition was that work was self-assigned. No one team member was told what they should work on or what process to use in approaching their responsibilities. From kickoff to launch, the entire project was created in a sum of two weeks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Full website: &lt;a href=&quot;http://beardswipe.me&quot;&gt;Beardswipe.me&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;




&lt;div class=&quot;grid&quot;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;grid__item grid__item--two-thirds&quot;&gt;
        &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/beardswipe/image1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Web&quot;&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;grid__item grid__item--one-third&quot;&gt;
        &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/beardswipe/image2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;iOS Design&quot;&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;




&lt;div class=&quot;content--post&quot;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;What I Worked on&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I choose to tackle both design and development of the product website. Knowing that it was to be released as an April Fools joke, I wanted the visual design to mock recent trends while still keeping a streamlined user experience that supported the campaign.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;




&lt;div class=&quot;content--post&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Wireframes&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Working to get in code as soon as possible, I did a quick mockup of interactions with notes on functionality I needed to tackle straight away in code. I handed these to my copywriter who delved into creating some of the snarky commentary.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;




&lt;div class=&quot;grid&quot;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;grid__item grid__item--half&quot;&gt;
        &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/beardswipe/image4.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Wires&quot;&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;grid__item grid__item--half&quot;&gt;
        &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/beardswipe/image3.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Sketches&quot;&gt;
        &lt;br&gt;
        &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/beardswipe/image5.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Sketches&quot;&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;




&lt;div class=&quot;content--post&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Art Direction&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We wanted the website to appeal to what we liked to call the &#39;urban woodsman&#39;, a special breed of bearded man who owned both an axe and a fixed gear bicycle. To reflect this, I chose to use the gold iphone in the designs and pulled out some of that gold to use as accents.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also wanted the visual design to be a nod to startup website design trends common around April 2014, as a slight mockery since the product was actually fake. This is why I choose Brandon Grotesque and Helvetica Neue as my base fonts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;




&lt;div class=&quot;grid&quot;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;grid__item grid__item--half&quot;&gt;
        &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/beardswipe/image6.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Web&quot;&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;grid__item grid__item--half&quot;&gt;
        &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/beardswipe/brt.gif&quot; alt=&quot;BRT&quot;&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;grid&quot;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;grid__item grid__item--half&quot;&gt;
        &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/beardswipe/image7.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Responsive&quot;&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;grid__item grid__item--half&quot;&gt;
        &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/beardswipe/image8.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Overlapping CSS tricks&quot;&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/beardswipe/image9.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Full comp&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</summary>
      <id>//beardswipe.html</id>
      <updated>2014-08-28T09:57:51-07:00</updated>
      <author>
        <name>Klare Frank</name>
      </author>
    </entry>
  
    <entry>
      <title>Everything Looks the Same: Convergence of Web Design</title>
      <link href="//everything-looks-the-same.html" />
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;To preface, this was my original proposed topic for &lt;a href=&quot;http://contrarycon.com&quot;&gt;Contrary Con&lt;/a&gt;. If you&#39;ve never prepped for a talk for a conference before, it&#39;s a lot of hard work. Being that it was my first official conference speaking experience, it took most nights (and some mornings) the week of plus extra concepting the week prior. I have a lot more respect now for speakers who can craft engaging and cohesive talks that aren&#39;t focused around their work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While I enjoyed speaking on the principles I practice for trying to create quality work and how it transcends one project to affect my future work and the work of my peers, a lot of attendees really wanted to hear about the original topic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So here we go.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;How did we get here?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you were designing two or three years ago, you&#39;ll remember most homepages had four elements. A header, a carousel, a three column section with more content that no one read, and a very large footer with a complete sitemap and contact information.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In short, something very similar to this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/old-websites.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;2010 era websites&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During that time, most people thought this was the perfect layout. We kept seeing more clients request this and never stray from it. Conveniently, it worked well for clients who always wanted their content &quot;above the fold&quot;. We thought things wouldn&#39;t change too much.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But things did change.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not too long after, responsive design emerged. Some people (including myself) adopted it early on, while others were skeptical for a long while, arguing that separate mobile sites were better. Regardless, responsive design became the norm, and as creators of the web, we adapted to this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What we ended up with were longer websites where content could be delivered in more interesting layouts. These layouts were based on strict grid systems that could be easily reconfigured into a single column for small screens.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They ended up looking a bit like this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/new-websites.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;2013 era websites&quot; /&gt;
&lt;cite&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://graphicburger.com/one-page-website-wireframes/&quot;&gt;Created with One Page Wireframes&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But frankly, things still look the same.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Why is it that today we have more flexibility in delivering content, yet we&#39;re creating websites that look nearly identical to one another?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Visual trends as response&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you remember (or maybe you&#39;d like to forget), highly texturized, drop shadowed websites were popular at the same time we were creating websites that were only 800 pixels tall. I think a lot of the justification for creating these was based off of our layouts being so rigid. Creating a website with personality was tough when services such as Typekit and Fontdeck were just emerging.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Additionally, after so many of our websites were just links for a long while, it was nice to be able to include a lot of images that didn&#39;t take forever to load. It was pretty much commonplace to create websites where all the text had a 1px shadow to make it feel inset on the page, echoing actual letter-pressed, real type.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/pendulum-1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Pendulum&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In contrast, the minimalistic flat design was a response to this highly texturized trend.  If you remember, responsive design emerged during this time. While we were reluctant to let go of sites that could be designed &#39;pixel perfect&#39;, we realized it was simply easier to create responsive designs for existing websites if they had less decoration and less superfluous content.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/pendulum-2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Pendulum&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But it was more than that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let&#39;s take a look at some of the things that have influenced how we currently design for the web.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Responsive Design&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Things had to change, literally.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As mentioned before, responsive design was a huge influence on simplifying websites.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Starting out, designers and developers needed to get familiar with responsive design. To accommodate changing sizes and placement of elements within responsive layouts, websites were mostly distilled down into a collection of large boxes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Creating a website became more difficult to complete within the same timeframe. It&#39;s understandable that websites got simpler in response to this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;Flexibility has become a more valuable currency than specificity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Matt Griffin — &lt;a href=&quot;http://alistapart.com/article/client-relationships-and-the-multi-device-web&quot;&gt;Client Relationships and the Multi-Device Web&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Type&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I like to joke that everything is either set in Proxima Nova or Brandon Grotesque. Or maybe Gotham if the client is really &quot;progressive&quot; (aka, was convinced to pay a lot for a Hoefler &amp;amp; Co typeface).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&#39;s mostly true. Take a look at &lt;a href=&quot;http://land-book.com/&quot;&gt;Land Book&lt;/a&gt; and you&#39;ll see the most recent startup homepages featured are set in these typefaces.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They&#39;re all modern sans-serifs that are easy to read and work with a variety of different logos. In short, very flexible. Yet, overuse dilutes any uniqueness.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Bootstrap&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I get it. It&#39;s easy to use. &lt;a href=&quot;http://getbootstrap.com/&quot;&gt;Bootstrap&lt;/a&gt; can be a great tool for quickly creating prototypes. However, when a product gets built using Bootstrap, it can be easy to think the work has been done.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It works.
It feels like a real product.
It has whitespace.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, over time we&#39;ve noticed that websites built with bootstrap still look like bootstrap. Heck, even toolkits based off bootstrap look like bootstrap.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;Deciding all the components in a toolkit before starting design is limiting designers to what&#39;s already been done, not what&#39;s possible.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;How similar is too similar?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I came across these two websites in May of 2014, my initial thought was that someone took a hell of a lot of influence from the other. I posted to twitter with a simple reaction of &#39;huh&#39;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/BndmDgaCAAAAtZ9.png&quot; alt=&quot;May 2014&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Immediately after, I was reminded that this trend is prevalent in a lot of places. Take for example InVision&#39;s latest redesign, which also uses similar placement of user interface elements and the same font and treatment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/Bndn8MKCMAMUz4r.png&quot; alt=&quot;May 2014&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So how similar is too similar? Is this a reflection of trends and influence or designers drawing the same conclusions?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;What should we do (if anything)?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most people are quick to judge today&#39;s websites, but there are some positives to their similarity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Users know where to go. Most of the common elements on a page are in similar places and take advantage of users scanning the page in an &#39;F&#39; shaped pattern.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It&#39;s easy for startups to build first, validate their product and then add on uniqueness.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The design similarities make websites of today look a hell of a lot better than their predecessors.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;


&lt;p&gt;We can do better than that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The web community has done a great job recently asking why certain trends exist and whether they add to the sites being created. But we shouldn&#39;t be critical for the sake of being critical.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As technology changes, our common web design philosophy will also change. It could be a positive response to having more flexibility in the way we create websites, or a negative responsive to using new technology in the same way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We&#39;ll see. Change is inevitable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not all of the solutions we&#39;ve used in today&#39;s very minimalist era work for every project. Web designers have already moved away from exceedingly flat design trends (such as long shadows). I predict that we&#39;ll see some bit of texture emerge as the pendulum swings back away from highly minimal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&#39;d challenge all of you creating websites to think about creating something that enhances the work with ever step.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary>
      <id>//everything-looks-the-same.html</id>
      <updated>2014-08-25T03:29:21-07:00</updated>
      <author>
        <name>Klare Frank</name>
      </author>
    </entry>
  
    <entry>
      <title>Design Process as Scientific Method</title>
      <link href="//design-process-as-scientific-method.html" />
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Let&#39;s face it. The last time I thought about the scientific method, it was probably in high school. Back when the chairs for those heavy, black-topped were too tall for your knees to fit underneath and wearing safety googles meant not being able to see through a level of dust and film left on the plastic from years of science classes. I never ended up practicing anything close to science after high school so I don&#39;t have an intimate knowledge of the process, but I&#39;d like to think that there&#39;s something to be garnished from proven methodology.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Beyond all the awkwardness of teenage misunderstanding, one thing I never got to do in science class was actually use the scientific method as it was intended: as iteration. It builds in an understanding that failure is almost certain and we&#39;re never going to prove our hypothesis correct the first time (unless we&#39;re superhuman or cheating).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A traditional waterfall approach is much like the scientific method of high school, we go through the motions, but there&#39;s never a chance to go back to change our hypothesis and test again. Once one &#39;deliverable&#39; is signed off on, it&#39;s impossible to go back and change that part of the equation. If we&#39;re lucky, some testing may be done on wireframes or visual design comps, but once that phase is complete, it&#39;s very difficult to change. Waterfall protects teams from ever changing scopes and clients that can&#39;t decide on what they want, sure, but it also holds back teams from creating the best products.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yet, agile doesn&#39;t work for every project. So how can we adapt our traditional design process to factor in the near certainty that we will fail, not at everything, at something? I&#39;d like to think that we&#39;re all better designers tomorrow than today, and there have definitely been projects where I could&#39;ve gone back and fixed aspects of a design based on insights learned later on. Perhaps we should be treating both user experience and visual design in a frame much like the scientific method so we can iterate and bring more rigor to a design process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Applying the scientific method to a design phase&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let&#39;s take a look at the steps of the scientific method and see how to use them in terms of our own design process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Question&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These usually end up being more &#39;How&#39; questions than &#39;Why&#39;. Many times, these questions come from our kickoff meetings with our clients. We usually go through a few different exercises to prioritize goals. In one of our recent kickoffs, the top priorities were to increase conversions and simplify/automate specific parts of the cms. Let&#39;s take that one step further by turning them into questions. How can we increase conversions from the homepage to getting a person to sign up for a service? How can we simplify the cms so bulk content can be added and maintained automatically?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Hypothesis&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These are the educated guesses we take when we make design decisions. Only have one button on the homepage will increase clicks to that page. Friendly, family-oriented and candid photography relates with our top personas, making it more likely they&#39;ll explore the website. People want to fill out a contact form more than sending an email to an anonymous address.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Testing&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Design is executed. My preference is to test closest to production format (usually code), but some testing is better than none. Any time I&#39;ve done user testing, it becomes clear really quick if the assumptions I made while designing were correct or ended up confusing users. Asking the questions before designing also makes it easy to test since the questions already exist.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Analysis&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is where all the testing results are sorted through to identify if our hypotheses were correct or incorrect. New hypotheses, execution and testing may be needed and should be planned for now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Iteration&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We should assume that some of our hypotheses were wrong and build at least a phase of iteration into our design timeline before showing clients. Why? It makes it easier to defend any design decision to a client because it&#39;s been tested and proven. Instead of doing a shoulder shrug or coming up with some arbitrary design speak bullshit to defend a design, a designer can point to specific tests as reasons for decisions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;How is this different than just designing and testing?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well, for starters, testing gets built into the process instead of getting placed at the end of a phase. Instead of designing while these assumptions arise, hypotheses specifically get created to test answer our key questions before starting any design. This helps narrow focus during the design phase down to the main goals identified for any web build. When testing starts, the specific things to test for are already noted through our key questions and hypotheses. Additionally, analysis of tests provides strong documentation and defense for any design decision, both for ux and visual design.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Adding in this methodology to a timeline may lengthen it, so any team needs to seriously consider where they need to cut the fat. (Personally, I think it exists in visual comp deliverables, but knowing code, I can be very biased.) What it does is strengthen and defend designs, helping them become better by adding in iteration and testing through specific questions and assumptions.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary>
      <id>//design-process-as-scientific-method.html</id>
      <updated>2014-07-14T04:47:21-07:00</updated>
      <author>
        <name>Klare Frank</name>
      </author>
    </entry>
  
    <entry>
      <title>Simple Content Audits</title>
      <link href="//content-audits.html" />
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;When starting any redesign of a current website, you need to know the existing content you have to work with. It&#39;s the building blocks of starting a lessons learned about what worked on the current site and what didn&#39;t so you can build a better site moving forward. Complete documentation always helps when you&#39;re not exactly sure what you need moving forward.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Grabbing all the content&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I ran &lt;a href=&quot;http://istrategylabs.com&quot;&gt;iStrategyLabs.com&lt;/a&gt; through the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.content-insight.com/&quot;&gt;Content Analysis Tool&lt;/a&gt;, which crawls through the site grabbing all the pages and providing data including how many images, media and documents are on a page. This was a lot more thorough than going through the istrategylabs.com site by hand and listing the pages in a spreadsheet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After I imported the information from the Content Analysis Tool into a Google spreadsheet, I organized the pages to reflect our existing sitemap. This was just to confirm that the tool worked as I intended and I had all the information necessary to move forward.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Gathering Observations&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Doing an audit on existing pages, images, media and documents is great, but it isn&#39;t enough. After you have all the content, you need to go through and identify the good and not so great parts about your current content. These are the things I looked for after all the pages on the site were listed and organized into a format reflecting our current sitemap.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Duplicate information&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; This ones pretty straightforward. We found several instances of pages created for the intention of redirects. Also, several blog posts were created as project recaps when they really should&#39;ve been work case studies.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Pages that were created as a temporary solution.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; As mentioned above, project recap posts would be created in addition to work pages. Since our work section couldn&#39;t accommodate an explanation of our process, or more than a couple of paragraphs and a dozen images, blog posts were used to supplement. On our new site, we&#39;re planning on doing only case studies for all new work, solving the disconnect between work and blog posts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; Another outlier was the link to the case study deck underneath work. I flagged that as another place where new pages were being adapted to suit needs instead of the site working for us.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Understanding the breadth of existing content&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; I had initially thought our site would have a lot of hidden and superfluous pages, but it ended up being straightforward. Our biggest content, not surprisingly, came from blog posts and work, followed by team bios, author pages and categories. Our blog is a HUGE deal. Just imagine if all the teams wrote regularly, and not just strategy &amp;amp; clever girl.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Content in wrong areas&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; As mentioned before, our work content also existed on our blog, along with a huge amount of physical experiments that could&#39;ve been more highlighted.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Keep/Kill&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; If you removed this section, could the site still exist and make sense?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; We had a lengthy debate in our kickoff meeting on whether we should keep or kill individual team bios. The real question you should be asking when doing a content audit is what value that content is added to a site overall.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;


&lt;h2&gt;Evaluating the quality of content&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After the types of content to trim from the site and reorganizing similar content into more sensible areas, you still need to evaluate if the content on the site is any good. Simply having these pages and content on the pages isn&#39;t enough. The content and types of content have to be great enough to keep users on the site and get them interested. Is the about page written in the best way to attract clients and potential hires? Does the work section present information in a way that entices users to keep looking or get in content with us?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a designer, one of my primary goals in evaluating content is to help create a design that supports the copy and the audience it was written for. Creating a solid, cohesive experience depends entirely on the content working alongside the targeted design.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;What next?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now that there&#39;s great base documented, new content can be written to fill gaps and ux design can easily get started with wireframes based on identified content types needed on existing and new pages.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary>
      <id>//content-audits.html</id>
      <updated>2014-07-07T03:29:21-07:00</updated>
      <author>
        <name>Klare Frank</name>
      </author>
    </entry>
  
    <entry>
      <title>EveryoneOn</title>
      <link href="//everyoneon.html" />
      <summary type="html">&lt;div class=&quot;hero&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/everyoneon/hero.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;div class=&quot;content--post&quot;&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Project Overview&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Originally the Connect2Compete program, EveryoneOn came to iStrategyLabs to combine the two brands under one redesigned website. With a focus on information architecture and design, ISL worked with the EveryoneOn team to reorganize content and present it in a simple, digestible, mobile-friendly format.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The team at iStrategyLabs and I built a complete website that combined two previous websites and brands (Connect2Compete and EveryoneOn). This was especially challenging considering the wide range of audiences (children and families, job-seekers, and seniors). With a focus on information architecture and design, we worked with the EveryoneOn team to reorganize content and present it in a simple, digestible, mobile-friendly format.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;div class=&quot;content--post&quot;&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Information Architecture&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As mentioned, we were combining two websites together, which involved a comprehensive look at the content.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;What we started with&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;div class=&quot;grid__item grid__item--half&quot;&gt;
        &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/everyoneon/image1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Existing Sitemap&quot;&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;


&lt;div class=&quot;content--post&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Final sitemap&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/everyoneon/image2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Final Sitemap&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;content--post&quot;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Wireframes&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This was my first experience in deliberately choosing to do in-browser wireframes. I wanted the client and our entire team to see how the website might feel with actual content at different screen sizes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also provided an annotated version of the wireframes. This allowed me to tie certain sections directly to our audience and goals.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;




&lt;div class=&quot;grid&quot;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;grid__item grid__item--half&quot;&gt;
        &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/everyoneon/image3.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Annotated Wireframes&quot;&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;grid__item grid__item--half&quot;&gt;
        &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/everyoneon/image4.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;In-browser Wireframes&quot;&gt;
        &lt;br&gt;
        &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/everyoneon/image5.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;In-browser Wireframes&quot;&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;




&lt;div class=&quot;content--post&quot;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Visual Design&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Typography&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I wanted to choose a typefaces that were friendly and approachable to help the website seem more inviting to our wide range of audiences.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/everyoneon/type.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Type&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;content--post&quot;&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Adelle&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Chosen because of it&#39;s personality and flexibility that, when paired with a softer typeface, adds an element of authority. In the context of this website, it was used exclusively for headlines.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;Proxima Nova Soft&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A more approachable rounded version of Proxima Nova. I almost always chose to pair this with Adelle to soften the slab serif.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;Effra&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A sans-serif known for it&#39;s clean lines and open proportions that create a geometric and modern typeface.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;




&lt;div class=&quot;content--post&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Color&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;EveryoneOn already had a color palette of red and blue. I choose to tweak the colors slightly so that they were less harsh and more youthful while adding a darker blue to balance out whitespace.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/everyoneon/color.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;iOS Design&quot;&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/everyoneon/image6.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Large&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;grid&quot;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;grid__item grid__item--two-thirds&quot;&gt;
        &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/everyoneon/image7.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Medium&quot;&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;grid__item grid__item--one-third&quot;&gt;
        &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/everyoneon/image8.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Small&quot;&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/everyoneon/image9.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Small&quot;&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/everyoneon/image10.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Small&quot;&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/everyoneon/image11.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Small&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</summary>
      <id>//everyoneon.html</id>
      <updated>2014-06-15T09:57:51-07:00</updated>
      <author>
        <name>Klare Frank</name>
      </author>
    </entry>
  
    <entry>
      <title>Faking Responsive</title>
      <link href="//faking-responsive.html" />
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Responsive design has been forcing digital agencies for the past few years to rethink their traditional waterfall processes. It&#39;s tough enough trying to nail down a visual design when your client is deliberating over the font size of navigation items, asking questions like: &quot;Why can&#39;t we decrease the size of the carousel to view more items below the fold?&quot;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yes. We all still get asked this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In an ideal world, all designers would be able to flawlessly code up their designs and browser test them (because we know someone&#39;s bound to be viewing the page in IE). Presenting to clients and iterating through designs based on feedback would be as simple as changing a few backgrounds, images and placements of elements in Photoshop or Illustrator. We can&#39;t all have that. A girl can hope, right?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Working on a design team with several designers on the same project has taught me to be extremely flexible in the methods we use to create and present work to clients. Some designers know code. Great. Some designers are wizs at Illustrator. Also great. We all have different tools we prefer and work quickly in. I love that some people on my team know more about certain tools and we all still make great designs using different methods.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But at the end of the day, we&#39;re still presenting a picture of the website we intend to create. Faking responsive with static comps gets us one step closer by allowing the client to view the correct sizing of type, elements and images based on their viewport. But how do we do that?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Let&#39;s make a simple page&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let&#39;s start off by assuming we&#39;ll still have static comps. Because we&#39;re trying to be really nice to our developers, we&#39;re also creating separate comps for our viewports that are sized appropriately based on width.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I like to start in Sketch with their &#39;Web Design&#39; template, which gives us four artboards: Desktop HD at 1440 pixels wide, Desktop at 1024 pixels wide, Tablet Portrait at 768 pixels wide, and Mobile Portrait at 320 pixels wide. As a side note, we probably want to make sure we&#39;re saving these both @1x and at @2x in case our client is on a retina device.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/responsive-comps.png&quot; alt=&quot;Example of Sketch document with four different artboards&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next, we want a simple html page with a css file attached where we list out all of our comp images. We also want to make sure we&#39;re adding a class to each image so we can reference that in css.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;body&amp;gt;
    &amp;lt;img src=&quot;_/img/comp_desktophd.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;desktophd&quot;&amp;gt;
    &amp;lt;img src=&quot;_/img/comp_desktop.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;desktop&quot;&amp;gt;
    &amp;lt;img src=&quot;_/img/comp_laptop.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;laptop&quot;&amp;gt;
    &amp;lt;img src=&quot;_/img/comp_tablet.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;tablet&quot;&amp;gt;
    &amp;lt;img src=&quot;_/img/comp_mobile.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;mobile&quot;&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;/body&amp;gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But this shows all the images and we only want to show the one that fits the viewport for our user. So in css, we&#39;ll hide all the elements and display only the one that corresponds to our comp width:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;@media screen and (min-width: 1024px) {
    .desktophd, .desktop, .laptop, .tablet, .mobile {
        display: none;
    }
    .desktop {
        display: block;
        width: 100%;
    }
}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since our desktop comp is 1024 pixels wide, we&#39;ll show that when the user&#39;s viewport is at 1024 pixels or higher while hiding everything else.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Repeat with each comp and we&#39;ll have something like this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/responsive-comps.gif&quot; alt=&quot;Viewport width adjusting to show different comps at different browser widths&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Upload to a server and now we have a url that we can send to our clients. When they open the page, only the image that fits their viewport will show so that we can be sure they&#39;re viewing our designs proportionately.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Caveats&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This doesn&#39;t solve everything. Like the title of this post suggests, we&#39;re only faking responsive. We still have problems like not being able to show interactive elements, transitions, parallax (if you insist on using it), etc. At the end of the client meeting, the comps are still pretty pictures of a website we&#39;ll eventually make.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You could probably be really fancy with how you serve your images, too. But we&#39;re going for simplicity here, so that&#39;s why I wrote it the way I did.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This does, however, attempt to solve the issue of the client thinking designs are really really large, or wanting to know how our desktop sized comps will look on their ipad. And sometimes that&#39;s exactly what we need to get signoff on visual designs.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary>
      <id>//faking-responsive.html</id>
      <updated>2014-06-04T02:58:21-07:00</updated>
      <author>
        <name>Klare Frank</name>
      </author>
    </entry>
  
    <entry>
      <title>Paying for College</title>
      <link href="//paying-for-college.html" />
      <summary type="html">&lt;div class=&quot;hero&quot;&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/paying-for-college/image10.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;




&lt;div class=&quot;content--post&quot;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;The Problem&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Student debt can be a confusing arena where it&#39;s often difficult to understand how to compare the financial benefits of getting a college degree. Getting a college degree is often a part of the American dream, but students and parents taking on this debt often fail to realize the debt burden after school.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;What We Built&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a part of the products team at the Consumer Financial Protection Bureau, CFPB, I primarily worked as a visual designer, prototyping my ideas in code and working with other ux designers in sprint cycles to release Paying for College, a set of tools catered towards the education life milestone. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;See and interact with the current tool:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.consumerfinance.gov/paying-for-college/compare-financial-aid-and-college-cost/&quot;&gt;Paying for College Cost Comparision Tool&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;div class=&quot;grid&quot;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;grid__item grid__item--half&quot;&gt;
        &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/paying-for-college/image11.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;grid__item grid__item--half&quot;&gt;
        &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/paying-for-college/image12.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;div class=&quot;content--post&quot;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;What I Worked On&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;UX&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://brouin.com&quot;&gt;Brittany Mederos&lt;/a&gt; and I collaborated on how to build this tool, whiteboarding out different scenarios that we&#39;d both elaborate on and test. We ran into issues of how users were going to input data (if at all), how we would integrate two-year and four-year programs, and how to easily compare costs of different programs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;




&lt;div class=&quot;content--post&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Interface Design&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Paying for College was meant to be an extension of the Consumer Financial Protection Bureau brand. It drew inspiration from light usage of color on the rest of the website while focusing primarily on interactions. One of the more interesting parts of the interface was the sticky input header that allowed users to easily switch between schools, and the sticky footer containing important debt information that would attach itself to the bottom of the page once the user reached far enough down the cost table.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;div class=&quot;grid&quot;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;grid__item grid__item--two-thirds&quot;&gt;
        &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/paying-for-college/image8.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;grid__item grid__item--one-third&quot;&gt;
        &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/paying-for-college/image6.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;div class=&quot;grid&quot;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;grid__item grid__item--half&quot;&gt;
        &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/paying-for-college/image9.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;grid__item grid__item--half&quot;&gt;
        &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/paying-for-college/image7.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;




&lt;!-- ![The Interface](/assets/img/cfpb-paying-for-college-tool.png)
 --&gt;



</summary>
      <id>//paying-for-college.html</id>
      <updated>2014-05-26T09:57:51-07:00</updated>
      <author>
        <name>Klare Frank</name>
      </author>
    </entry>
  
    <entry>
      <title>Why I Switched to Sketch</title>
      <link href="//why-i-switched-to-sketch.html" />
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;It&#39;s been about two months since I decided to redownload Sketch and see what all the fuss was about. Surprisingly, I ended up liking it. Quite a lot. I&#39;ve switched from grumbling about having to use Photoshop to, now, just mocking up a few components and playing with layouts in Sketch outside of the context of browser constraints or grids already set in sass.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But first, let me put in context why I even using a program to design at all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Being a designer and frontend dev, my ideal workflow is to do everything besides design assets in browser. If I&#39;m working alone, this workflow is excellent for quickly iterating. But, when a project&#39;s team expands from a solo adventure to an expedition (yes, complete with guns, machetes and porters), it&#39;s tough to iterate in code. (Of course, that all changes if I&#39;m designing an app.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My creative director and my client aren&#39;t going to understand that I&#39;m trying to carve a Statue of David out of content and code and by iteration 4, it&#39;ll be there. They want to see how it&#39;ll look. In two days. So sometimes you need to make sacrifices in your own ideal process to fit a team balance. That&#39;s where a design app comes in. There&#39;s nothing wrong with using photoshop. Lots of designers use photoshop and produce great work. Some of them code, some of them don&#39;t. We all have different processes that work for each of us.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;You do you.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Things I enjoy now that I&#39;ve been using sketch exclusively for the past two months:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Artboards &amp;amp; Pages&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yup. I totally realize that you get this with illustrator. I don&#39;t disagree with you illustrator users! Artboards are awesome! They make iterating ideas quick by just drag-copying entire artboards. I can see what different interaction states look like right next to one another. If I need to create traditional comps because I know another designer may take over the work, it&#39;s easy to store a whole set of pages in one file. The organization is already set up to use and it&#39;s easy to understand.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Symbols &amp;amp; Shared Styles&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Photoshop has this, but, let&#39;s be real, it sucks. Yesterday I imported a fellow designer&#39;s comp from Photoshop to Sketch and create a symbol out of her button style. I ended up not using the button at all in the initial design I created, but when the edits came back from the client, I needed that button and it was easily stored for me to add in a second.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Type Rendering&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&#39;m not spending 5 million years switching between crisp, strong, mac, mac lcd, etc. Type in Sketch is closely rendered the way it&#39;ll look in modern browsers. I like that. Then I can spend less time wondering why it doesn&#39;t look similar and move on to spending 5 million years adjusting my margins.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Exporting&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I can geek out by exporting all my artboards and pages with &lt;a href=&quot;http://jonohunt.tumblr.com/post/84511158113/alfred-workflow-export-sketch-documents&quot;&gt;one command via Alfred&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Things I&#39;ve noticed need a bit of work:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Sketch can get a bit slow if you have a ton of artboards. I&#39;ve gotten around this by moving artboards to pages when I&#39;m mostly done with them.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Shared styles also share a color, so if you have type in a font and at one size, but want to change the color to white because it&#39;s on a dark background, you have to unlink the style first.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Sometimes resizing icons imported from illustrator can be strange. The inner shape might not resize exactly the right way.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Overall, I&#39;ve been pretty happy with the switch and have only opened Photoshop if another design gets handed to me. I&#39;ve really been loving all the plugins that keep popping up. It seems like the majority of users are really into open source and already are active on github. Sketch has been working great for me. If you&#39;re struggling with one tool, maybe you should give something else a try for a while. If you&#39;re not, then keep on designing! It&#39;s all a means to a polished final product and whatever&#39;s going to help you produce the best work is what you should be using.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary>
      <id>//why-i-switched-to-sketch.html</id>
      <updated>2014-05-15T07:32:51-07:00</updated>
      <author>
        <name>Klare Frank</name>
      </author>
    </entry>
  
    <entry>
      <title>What DC lacks</title>
      <link href="//what-dc-lacks.html" />
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I couldn&#39;t really put my finger on it until I left DC. Everyone talks about how transient this city is. I&#39;ve been victim to this common thread, having two of my best friends move to different cities in the past few months. I&#39;m happy for them to start a new adventure and gather new perspectives and experiences they weren&#39;t getting from living in DC. But eventually, most everyone packs up for somewhere new.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The second thing everyone talks about is the two same question you get asked when you meet someone new. I&#39;ve heard these questions differ from city to city, but it&#39;s become such of a commonality that folks expect it when you first meet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;What do you do?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I usually tell people I&#39;m a web designer and wait for the confused faces or the polarized comments about my CEO. It&#39;s a fun game when they&#39;re expecting me to ask them same question and I never do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;People usually say it&#39;s because you get judged immediately on your worth on the career climbing totem pole. I have another theory. On the surface, we&#39;re judged on the things we do, not our character. Bring up any okcupid profile and it&#39;ll list a passion for running, cooking, and traveling. You get points for being more interesting and unexpected in the things you do. Since a job makes up the majority of what a person does from day to do, it gets added to those points. It&#39;s only natural when talking about the things you do to mention (besides sleep) the thing you do the majority of the day: your job.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;In France, I&#39;ve heard, it&#39;s rude to ask people what they do.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How much of DC&#39;s culture has permiated down into my core, making it impossible for me to divorce my career from my personality? It&#39;s extremely tough as a designer not to notice things like kerning and typography on everything, but I enjoy making a distinction between my job and my career.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Where are you from?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is where I usually wait for the comments on Delaware beaches or something about incorporating in Wilmington. My conversationalist is usually looking for some commonality between the two of us, which may be likely since most everyone in DC is from somewhere else. I&#39;m from the second smallest state and I didn&#39;t live at the beach or in a corporation, so there&#39;s not much to say.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These questions aren&#39;t bad, but people end up complaining because they&#39;re so surface level. It&#39;s easy to start a conversation with a broad question like the two above, but we get stuck in this surface level slush instead of sinking down into the rabbit hole.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;People who live in DC have a hidden defense mechanism. It&#39;s like they know everyone&#39;s going to leave eventually so making deep connections isn&#39;t that much of a priority. Add big government and being treated like a number to the mix and suddenly a culture of detached professionals permiates through everything.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&#39;ve fallen victim to this as well. It&#39;s easy not to get too attached. But it&#39;s also monotonous. The meaty, rich parts of life come from deeper connections between people and the only way to get that is to be more empathetic in our relationships. I&#39;m going to start small and try to keep empathy in the front of my mind. It&#39;s not going to change the city, and I&#39;m not trying to solve all the problems, but it&#39;s a start. Small steps.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary>
      <id>//what-dc-lacks.html</id>
      <updated>2014-04-19T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
      <author>
        <name>Klare Frank</name>
      </author>
    </entry>
  
    <entry>
      <title>Ducklings</title>
      <link href="//ducklings.html" />
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Last night I taught my first class at General Assembly on the basics of HTML. Not only was it the first class of the course, but it was my first class ever. For the better part of three months I&#39;ve been dealing with impostor syndrome because I&#39;m teaching a frontend development course. As a designer. I&#39;d nervously laugh as I told people I&#39;d be sitting on a panel about the &#39;Day in the Life of a Frontend Developer&#39; when that wasn&#39;t my job title at all, and they&#39;d look at me like I was crazy for even thinking I &lt;em&gt;wasn&#39;t&lt;/em&gt; capable of being on that panel.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When it got time to actually teach, I wasn&#39;t nervous about being discovered as a fraud. They wouldn&#39;t have hired me if they didn&#39;t think I wasn&#39;t capable of teaching the materials. Obviously. Instead, I was more nervous about not remembering everyone&#39;s name and properly communicating the concepts to all my students.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Learning how to code was mostly a solitary pursuit for me. My parents tried to get my brother to learn how to program on the old Apple 2 Plus that used to sit in our office behind the Compaq loaded up with Windows 95, but I was never encouraged as much to learn. It wasn&#39;t until middle school, when I started surfing the net that I wondered how people made websites and started researching as much as I could.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yet, while most developers google and sit in their own little bubbles most of the time, sometimes it&#39;s just easier to ask someone more experiences.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;There&#39;s something magical about having the support and structure that comes from a mentor.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I never really got javascript until I had a mentor and we built a webapp using knockout.js. It&#39;s funny when you take on something you think you&#39;re not capable of and things just click.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, being on the other side of that relationship, I really hoping that I can inspire my students with that same feeling of awe at building something from scratch and having it come to life. That&#39;s the feeling that lets me know I wouldn&#39;t want to be in any other career.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary>
      <id>//ducklings.html</id>
      <updated>2014-04-09T09:57:51-07:00</updated>
      <author>
        <name>Klare Frank</name>
      </author>
    </entry>
  
    <entry>
      <title>Some Highlights from Grok</title>
      <link href="//some-highlights-from-grok.html" />
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I was really damn excited going into my double header trip of Barcelona/Greenville. One new place, and one familiar place. Two years ago, I went to Grok for the first time and made some great friends that I&#39;ve kept in touch with on twitter and have run into over those two years at various conferences across the country.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://distilleryimage9.ak.instagram.com/5c5aeff6bb5311e3b33a12e185860505_8.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Printing my own shirt&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What I loved about Grok the first time was still present this year. Amazingly friendly people that you can walk right up to and start talking with and 10/20s where folks who are just starting out and people who are internet famous have equal say. But this year was so much more than that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was great to see Ish Burciaga, Brittany Murray, Matt D. Smith and Jeremiah Adkins again like two years hadn&#39;t gone by. It was also amazing to meet so many new folks, even those in my own city and close by. One of my coworkers even signed up which was nice happenstance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I go to conferences, I like to choose ones that aren&#39;t technical. Why travel all the way to a new city to sit through lectures on things you probably could&#39;ve learned by reading an article? Conferences are about making relationships and getting a new perspective for a little while so that when we get back to our own cities and jobs, we can be inspired to create amazing work and continue the conversations &amp;amp; collaboration. I&#39;m definitely not planning on leaving the relationships I started building at Grok in Greenville.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://distilleryimage0.ak.instagram.com/848591d4bc3911e3b7d60002c99b1c44_8.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Awesome photobombs&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In one of our 10/20s, blogging came up, and I mentioned that I&#39;ve never successfully been able to blog. Following Matt D. Smith&#39;s advice about not spending so much time debating about the design of your site, I&#39;ve designed this website in two days and chose jekyll. Maybe this blogging thing will work. Maybe it won&#39;t. But hopefully someone will get something out of it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Out of a few of my 10/20s, there was a word that kept getting mentioned that doesn&#39;t really come up in conversation much in DC. &lt;em&gt;Empathy&lt;/em&gt;. It&#39;s something that I know makes me work better, but it&#39;s so easy to be lazy (especially in DC). Empathizing with a client&#39;s mission instead of just understanding it helps me create better visual designs. Empathizing with my friends and acquaintances helps me deepen relationships.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think that&#39;s the thing I was searching for when I left DC bored and ready for adventure. I was bored when I met someone new because they asked the same DC questions: &quot;What do you do&quot; &amp;amp; &quot;Where are you from originally&quot;. But really, I was avoiding empathizing and as a result created barriers between myself and any new connection.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;What was lacking wasn&#39;t something I could find by traveling, but something I was missing in myself.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&#39;m going back to DC knowing what I actively have to work on. I haven&#39;t answered all the questions or figured out where exactly I should be or what I should be working on, but I&#39;m a little bit closer. It&#39;s a good feeling.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let&#39;s keep those conversations going, Grokers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://distilleryimage10.ak.instagram.com/c64c7854bc7e11e3affe0002c9c90082_8.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Joseph Abrams and me with cigars&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</summary>
      <id>//some-highlights-from-grok.html</id>
      <updated>2014-04-07T09:57:51-07:00</updated>
      <author>
        <name>Klare Frank</name>
      </author>
    </entry>
  
    <entry>
      <title>A Little Solo Travel</title>
      <link href="//a-little-solo-travel.html" />
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;My mom sent me an email a few days after I booked a flight to Barcelona. Sure, it was my first time traveling  by myself to Europe, but I would only be gone for five days (a super short trip in the scheme of things). I had been to Europe more times than I could count on two hands, and traveled home from a completely different city than where my flight leaving only a year prior. So when I woke up one morning with an email in my inbox telling me that she wished I didn&#39;t go off by myself (I received a similar email from my grandmother as well), I wrote it off as motherly worry. And it was. Mostly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;Confidence is a strange muscle. When you have it, everything is as easy as a fork gliding through a slice of cheesecake. It&#39;s a pretty damn sweet feeling.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All my life, whenever I&#39;d have to go someplace new or do something I&#39;d never done before, I&#39;d have to force myself. That funny, sick feeling in my gut would emerge and I&#39;d be so nervous that I&#39;d be planning my escape route in all possible situations. I spent most of my life being afraid of new situations and thinking I was an introvert. It took losing all my confidence completely and having a year of rebuilding to discover that I wasn&#39;t. I&#39;m just a reserved extrovert. With a lot of long pauses.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://distilleryimage9.ak.instagram.com/744ae5b0b77211e3a9cb127110f29a31_8.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;A sea pattern in the tiles on the sidewalk&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The best part about traveling solo is that you don&#39;t have to wait for anyone to make your plans. Hell, you don&#39;t even have to make plans. I still remember how upset my mother got in Prague when my father and I just decided to go sit outside at lunch for a few hours having beers instead of doing the things she had planned. So we sat for a while, enjoying the August weather, becoming fishes in our liters of beer with smug grins creeping across our faces because we only paid 30 koruna for everything. Different people have different traveling styles. Some people like to sit soak up the ambiance of a new place. Some people simply like to see the sights. Some enjoy having their itinerary mapped out entirely beforehand.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The second best part about traveling is that you get to strike up a conversation with anyone. I understand now why they call it striking up a conversation. Out of nothing, you strike a match and that flame that had not existed before is suddenly bright and dancing, and for a brief point in time, it&#39;s possible to light up anything or extinguish the flame in an instant. Far too often, we rely on happenstance to meet someone new instead of actively creating these moments. Once I grew my confidence, I started to look forward to these moments I could make happen. One of my best conversations was when I met a professor from Drexel at a coffee shop and started talking to him about the quirks of different cities and how it&#39;s hard to find new and interesting coffee.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://distilleryimage1.ak.instagram.com/17f31dbcb8dc11e38e6212bdd7da67ad_8.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;A selfie looking out over Barcelona from Park Guell&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My only regret from the trip was that it was too short. Thankfully, I&#39;ve already booked another flight, this time to Seattle, since I haven&#39;t been able to get the emerald city out of my head for a year and a half.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let&#39;s go!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://distilleryimage0.ak.instagram.com/7382750ab9cd11e38efb0a406416de40_8.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Looking out over the wing of the plane at Barcelona and the coast&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</summary>
      <id>//a-little-solo-travel.html</id>
      <updated>2014-04-05T09:57:51-07:00</updated>
      <author>
        <name>Klare Frank</name>
      </author>
    </entry>
  
    <entry>
      <title>CourtPlay</title>
      <link href="//courtplay.html" />
      <summary type="html">&lt;div class=&quot;hero&quot;&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/courtplay/image1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Homepage&quot;&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;div class=&quot;content--post&quot;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Project Overview&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Earning a living as a professional tennis coach can be difficult at times because of the complexities of scheduling between coach, player, and court. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;CourtPlay is an effort to make booking a tennis lesson effortless. A coach can manage their schedule, message players and receive payments via the web app. A player can search for coaches in their area, book lessons directly with them and pay them online.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;h2&gt;User Experience&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the biggest challenges was creating an interface that was simple enough for both coaches and players. This was especially challenging when we adding calendar bookings and payment of lessons through the dashboard.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;div class=&quot;grid&quot;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;grid__item grid__item--half&quot;&gt;
        &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/courtplay/image2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Userflow&quot;&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;grid__item grid__item--half&quot;&gt;
        &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/courtplay/image3.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Wireframes&quot;&gt;
        &lt;br&gt;
        &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/courtplay/image4.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Wireframes&quot;&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;!-- 
![CourtPlay](/assets/img/courtplay/user-flow.jpg)
 --&gt;


&lt;p&gt; &lt;div class=&quot;content--post&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Interface Design&lt;/h2&gt;


&lt;p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/courtplay/image5.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Dashboard&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;grid&quot;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;grid__item grid__item--half&quot;&gt;
        &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/courtplay/image6.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Dashboard messages&quot;&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;grid__item grid__item--half&quot;&gt;
        &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/courtplay/image8.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Profile&quot;&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/courtplay/image7.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Dashboard&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- 
![CourtPlay](/assets/img/courtplay/homepage.jpg)

![CourtPlay](/assets/img/courtplay/dashboard-home.jpg)

![CourtPlay](/assets/img/courtplay/icons.jpg) --&gt;

</summary>
      <id>//courtplay.html</id>
      <updated>2014-03-20T09:57:51-07:00</updated>
      <author>
        <name>Klare Frank</name>
      </author>
    </entry>
  
    <entry>
      <title>CropLife</title>
      <link href="//croplife.html" />
      <summary type="html">&lt;div class=&quot;hero&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/croplife/croplife-vis-home.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Homepage&quot;&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;div class=&quot;content--post&quot;&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;The Problem&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;CropLife came to iStrategyLabs for a complete website redesign. They needed to combine two websites, croplife.org and actionforag.org, together into one site where members of the crop science community at large could search and browse through information related to the industry.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;What We Built&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We combined the two websites to create a cohesive repository of information stored in one place. Leveraging angular.js, we were able to quickly load resources, news, and case studies, making browsing through pages and pages of articles instantaneous without requiring page loads or ajax.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://croplife.org&quot;&gt;CropLife.org&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;h2&gt;What I Worked On&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I lead design through the discovery, wireframes and design phases, choosing user experiences that both fit the clients needs and that of their core user base.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Sitemap&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This was a particularly large web build with a lot of different pages, so it was important to identify templates for parent and child pages at the very beginning. A thorough sitemap was also helpful in crafting a content audit of both existing websites.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/croplife/croplife-sitemap.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Sitemap&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;content--post&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Wireframes&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I created static wireframes based on the templates identified from the sitemap and content audit, choosing a flexible layout for changing information. A split navigation separates the content between information about the crop science industry at large and information about CropLife as an organization. Limiting the homepage to one large background image carousel helps focus the website to the most relevant and recent news without cluttering the page, and thus, diverting attention from the most important items.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When creating the wireframes, I kept in mind the modularity for a large scale web build. Focusing on reusable components, I was able to start creating a framework for the whole website, lending to a cohesive experience, rather than a collection of pages.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/croplife/croplife-wireframes.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Wireframes&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;content--post&quot;&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Visual Design&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Starting in Photoshop, I experimented with different visual styles on a few of the main pages, presenting these comps to the client using Invision. Once a visual style was agreed upon, I moved into in-browser design, creating a working prototype of the website that the client could use as an example for key stakeholders. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;CropLife&#39;s existing brand had Gotham in varying weights as their main and secondary font. Since the majority of the website would be informational, with longer articles, I introduced a serif, FF Tisa, for readability and contrast.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I wanted to keep CropLife&#39;s bright green as the main focus of their brand while introducing other bright pops of color for interactions, when needed. Since CropLife already had a large repo of gorgeous crop photos, I wanted to use these as the main focal point to contrast long swatches of information in the main articles.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/croplife/croplife-vis-home2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Homepage&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/croplife/croplife-vis-interior.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Interior&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/croplife/croplife-vis-media.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Media&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/croplife/croplife-vis-resources.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Resources&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</summary>
      <id>//croplife.html</id>
      <updated>2014-02-09T08:57:51-08:00</updated>
      <author>
        <name>Klare Frank</name>
      </author>
    </entry>
  
</feed>
